Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Taylor Family Records - Wills, Deeds, Lands: Charles Day Data. Family records, wills, land deeds, Bucks County and Montgomery County supplements to NJ (Brookdale farm). The family lived off rented farmland income and the Sunberry? farm was kept as s (Box 8)
  - Emlen Hare Miller Correspondence, Laurel Hill Cemetery, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Data on Edward A. Spooner - Father of Louise Spooner and Taylor Marriage (Wife of F.W. Taylor), 1884 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Data on Death of James Anderson Wright, April 1931 (died 4-22-1930, related to F.W. Taylor) (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - F.W. Taylor Passport Search 1989, 1845-1989 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Business Correspondence of F.W. Taylor 1885-1898 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Sheet (12/28/87) on Relationships of Mrs. Sarah Push of Germantown and the Taylor Family, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Deed Search - Philadelphia 1989 (Fall), 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Wills in Bucks County Pennsylvania, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Copy of Taylor Will 1910 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Frederick W. Taylor and Louise M.S. Taylor, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    Yellow folder
  - Emma L. Taylor Will, Dec. 9, 1902 - Will # 24672 - Bucks County Historical Society - 9/10/90 Emma Taylor Will 1902, 1902-1990 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    Copies and original document
  - Kathy Drury (1988, on Emma Taylor Will) (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - 1988 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Wills of: Franklin Taylor Filed 11/8/1911 Bucks County Reel 24806 #1983, Emma L. Taylor Dec. 9, 1902, Sarah T. Allen Filed 3/10/1911 Book 104, p.138, # 1042, 1902-1911 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Franklin Taylor Material from Princeton Univ. 11/8/83, 1840-1916 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Taylor Family Wills, Sarah T. Allen filed 3/10/1911 (dated 1881), Emma L. Taylor dated 12/9/02, 1902-1911 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Lydia L.S. Taylor (Lydia Sharpless) Died Oct. 15, 1914 - Interstate - Wife of Dr. E. Winslow Taylor (see Genealogy of The Sharpless Family by Gilbert Cope) - Taylor Family, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Houston Dunn (Married Elsie Emsile Taylor), Bromley Wharton - Taylor Family, 1929-1991 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Benjamin Taylor Will 10-1-1918 - Taylor Family (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Caleb Taylor Letters of Administration 1988 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Letters on Administration Caleb Newbold on Land in Bucks County, January 14, 1888 - Taylor's Uncle (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Data on Caleb N. Taylor - 1987, Taylor Family (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Caleb Newbold Appeal of Taylor 1887 (Franklin Taylor - FW Father, Benjamin Taylor 1888), 1887-1888 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Enoch Taylor "Taylor Estate" (Appeal of Walker 1896) Atlantic Reporter, 34, PA, pp. 307-308 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Bucks County Maps, 1672-1784 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Historical Sources on Bucks County PA on Taylor's and NJ Data, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Caleb Taylor and Sunbury Farm, 1887-1988 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Data on Sunbury Farm - Newportville, PA - from David Jackson 3/25/90 - F.W. Taylor Family Farm, 1885-1990 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Caleb Taylor, Willets, and Charles, Taylor Land in Oakford, PA (North of 35th Ward of Phila) 1872 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Caleb Taylor - Uncle of F.W. Taylor, Died Newportville, PA 11-15-1887 "Sunbury Farm" (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Newbold Land in Bucks County (Maps 1891) - Taylor Book (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Atlas Maps of Montgomery County 1871, 1877 - Taylor Land, 1871-1893 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    Notebook and copies of original maps
  - Falls Township Map 1891 - Taylor Land (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Map of Bristol Township, Bucks County 1891 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Data on Bucks County Plat Maps (includes Caleb Newbold Taylor Land, Canby Land, Balderston Land), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Bensalem Map (Bucks County) Showing Caleb, C.W. Taylor, and Robert Taylor Land - Taylor Family, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Map of Bristol Township in Pennsylvania, 1890 - Showing Caleb Newbold Land (F.W. Taylor's Uncle) (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Bucks County Maps and Emma Taylor Will and Deeds, 1682-1784 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Caleb N. Taylor Land in Newportville, PA 1876 - Taylor Family, 1899-1988 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    Original and copies of documents
  - Maps of Bristol, PA 1891 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Lydia Sharpless and Edward Taylor 1990 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Emma L. Taylor Will, 12/9/02 (Lists Land in Phila) - Taylor Land, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence with Frank Wallace (100 Old York Road, Bordentown, NJ) 1989 - Taylor NJ (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Photograph of F.W. Taylor in American Golfer p. 418 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Golf Club Search for Old Taylor Photos 1978 - Taylor and Golf 1978, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Sam Oset Lodge Data and Taylor Golf Photo (Bay Point Hotel Purchased by the Ricker Hotel Company 1902 and became the Sam Oset) A.W. Hodgdon, Manager in 1909 - 1984 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Letters on Taylor and Golf 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Search for Taylor Golf Photos 1984 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Germantown Cricket Club Members 1893 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - History of Cricket (For Taylor Book), 1926 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence with U.S. Tennis Association, RE: F.W. Taylor 1979 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - W. Nightingale and 1881 Tennis Tournament, 1881-1931 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Ted Tinling - Taylor and Tennis, 1989 Taylor Book, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Tennis Data and Taylor, 1881-1979 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - The American Cricketeer on Tennis and Taylor - 1881, 1880-1881 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Nancy Matlaga Project Spring 1989, Mooney, Taylor, etc., Tennis Hall of Fame (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - F.W. Taylor and Tennis Research 1979, 1881-1979 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence with Mrs. Robert Harie on Tennis and Taylor 3/21/79 - Taylor and Tennis 1979 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Data on Joseph Clark, Sears and Dwight - Related to Taylor-Tennis Project, 1883-1979 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - General Robert Shaw Oliver - President of American Lawn Tennis Association 1881, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Cricket Clubs and Taylor's Hat, 1971-1989 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - The American Cricketer Data, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Germantown Newspaper Data 5/12/1883 on Siemen's Suit against Midvale (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Germantown Newspapers, 1795-1948 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Midvale Steel in Germantown Telegraph 9/1/1880 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Sketches of Old Germantown Maps of 1875, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Maps of Phila - Germantown and Midvale Steel 1885-1895 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - People in Philadelphia and Maps of Germantown, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Maps of Midvale Steel, Philip Justice Land in Nicetown 1889 and American Polley Company Site (owned by Manor Real Estate Co.) (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Note from Daniel Reeves 12/14/87 on Germantown Telegraph - May 21, 1884 on Rifled Cannons, May 28, 1884 Hammer Shop Completed - Midvale File, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Germantown Historical Society 1988 (old maps), 1893-1988 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Early Maps of Germantown, PA from NY Public Library Files - 1988 (Shows Midvale Steel Location and Taylor), 1835-1988 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - James Duffin - Germantown Historical Society 1987 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Germantown Independent, Feb. 4, 1887 Announcement of Purchase of Midvale by Harrah (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Maps of Germantown, December, 1987 with House Members and Midvale Steel (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Germantown Independent and Taylor, 1886-1988 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Charles Day Wrege Paper - NE Designing Sciences Institute 1987 (with reviews) (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Charles Day "Standen" Home in Chestnut Hill - 1932 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Letters with Mrs. John Dilks (St. George Rd. Phila) 1979 on Taylor - Charles Day, 1929-1979 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Correspondence on Charles Day 1987 (Mrs. John Dilks), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - Research Data on Charles Day - 1987, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Charles Day Research - 1980 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Charles Day Material Related to Taylor 1979 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Collection of Data on Charles Day 8/7/86, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Dodge and Day Betterment Report #144 (related to Taylor and early "Decision Times") (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Day and Zimmerman Progress 1919 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Data on Day and Zimmerman and Southern Ohio, P.S. Co. (Zanesville, 0210) 1926 - From Electric 1926 - Charles Day (Box 8, Folder 109)
- Taylor Records in Philadelphia. Gopsills City Directory supplement information on relatives, Justice family, Millers, Newbolds all related to each other and worked with Taylor.. (Box 9)
  - J.L. Boockholdt (on Acct. and Basley) - Basley (Acct), 1887 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Clark Elliott - Letter on F.W. Taylor's Letter to Beyerly on Education 12/4/78, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Data from Phila City Directories 1987, Taylor-Davenport, 1880-1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lee Bregy Description of Universal Testing Machine June 1991 (See Photo of Taylor at Midvale at This Machine) On Photo of Taylor at Midvale 1886 Showing Machine (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Joseph L. Ferrell Data (Phila), Taylor Apprentice of Ferrell, Gopsill's 1872 p.496, 1876 p.507, 1881 p.541, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Tennis Sept. 4, 1881 (NY Herald p. 9) on Taylor and Clark (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Research in Philadelphia on Colkett, Gilbert, ect. Taylor, 1865-1887 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Gopsill's Phila City Directory 1867 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Taylor" in Gopsill's Philadelphia 1882, 1883, 86, 87, 88 - Taylor Book, 1882-1888 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Gopsill's Phila. Directory Data for Taylor Book, 1875-1992 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Names to Check in Gopsill's - Taylor Book, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Gopsill's, Phila. 1879 For Taylor Book (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Gopsill's City Directory of Phila 1874 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 1875 Gopsills (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Data on Business in Philadelphia, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Addresses of Companies in Philadelphia, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Gopsill's Data Phila - On Taylor, 1995-1905 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Graduates of Stevens Institute of Technology, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Envelope with original documents and copies
  - Charles S. Hartle and William A. Fannen Letters on Taylor, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Persons Speaking at Memorial Service at Cedron, Oct. 1915 - Taylor Book, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    Original document and copy
  - Charles W. Shartle (Worked with Taylor at Midvale Steel Co. - Later Had Business at Middletown, Ohio) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Birge Harrison Letter on F.W. Taylor August 25, 1915 - Taylor Book (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - F.W. Taylor Obituaries 3/22/1915, Memorial Service 10/26/1915 - Taylor Obituaries (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Caspar Goodrich on Taylor 1915 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Charles Shartle Stories on Taylor, 1980-1984 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Letter on Taylor By Charles W. Shartle May 2, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Charles Shartle and F.W. Taylor - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - W. Fannon on F.W. Taylor 1916 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Memorial Meeting for F.W. Taylor 1915 List of Participants - Taylor Family (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Sanford Thompson Letter of 9/13/1915 on Dates in FWT Life (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - The Nation, April 1, 1915, p.349 on "The Science and Efficiency" and Taylor, After Taylor's Death (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Letters written to Kempton Taylor 1915 on F.W. Taylor (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - William A. Fannon - Letter 4/21/1916, Memories of Taylor (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Obituaries - Boston - McElwain, 1900-1983 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Obituaries of Phila People Related to F.W. Taylor 1989, 1908-1989 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Navy Cannon in Germantown Independent Dec. 23, 1882 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Rifled Cannon and Midvale - Letter to Foundry Museum Cold Spring, NY 10/30/87, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Joseph M. Califf, "The Development of the Modern High-Powered Rifled Cannon" Railroad and Engineering Jl. 1889 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Latrobe Steel Company Data 1988 (Related to Midvale, Letter to ADA Shapiro 1-7-88) (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Social Register Search 1989 (for Aertsen et al.) Aertsen, Taylor (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Aertsen 1915, Midvale Steel (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - History of Midvale in: Midvale Safety Bulletin, Dec. 1914, Jan, Feb, March 1915 (By G. Aertsen), 1914-1915 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Anthony Krisak on Aertsen's and Newbold Family, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    Envelopes and original documents
  - Guilliaem Aertsen - Midvale - Latrobe Steel (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Guilliemeau Aertsen (Midvale Historian) 11/24/87 - Taylor, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Aertsen, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Data on Guilliemeau Aertsen and Clarence Clark 1880-81 - Gopsill's Taylor Book, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Latrobe Steel Co. and Aertsen, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Aertsen (Guilliame) and Aertsen Family - Related to Taylor (Wrote 1915 History of Midvale), 1864-1915 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Balderston Family in Phila in Gopsill's City Directory 1860-1871 (Related to Taylor) (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Balderston and Taylor in Upper Makefield Township, PA (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Anthony Krisak - 27 Fleetwood Drive, Hamilton Square, NJ 08690, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Letter to R.A. Feiss on Taylor Laboratory 8/21/1950 (From Canby Balderston, Univ. of PA) (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - C.C. Balderston Papers - Univ. of Pennsylvania - 1995 Susan Stefanski Letter - Academy Historian (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - C. Canby Balderston on Frederick Emery Balderston - Calif. (Also Robert W. Step Children - Walter, Henry, Alice) - Balderston and Mrs. Taylor, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    Original documents and copy
  - Charles A. Brinley Obituary Record from Yale University 1987 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Charles A. Brinley Data - Midvale, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Charles A. Brinley, Taylor Book, 1869-1987 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Charles A. Brinley, Charles Edward Brinley and William West Frazier George Brinley Data and Midvale, 1880-1971 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Charles A. Brinley Letters 1873-1880, 1942-1990 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Data on Charles Brinley and Charles F. Frothingham 1886 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Charles E. Brinley Letter on Charles A. Brinley 9/5/42, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Brinley Family in Bucks County, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Brandeis - Taylor Letters at Stevens Institute of Technology 1982 - Taylor Book, 1910-1982 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Taylor Letter to Byerly on Future Education (Copy) (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Byerly Letter (Taylor to Byerly) (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Sherman Trimm on Byerly, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Will of Clarence M. Clark - Will Book 83, p. 433 Philadelphia - July 1, 1937 - Midvale (Taylor Family) (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Frederick W. Clark Correspondence, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Bayard Clark 4100 Cathedral Ave. NCU #820, Wash. D.C. 20016, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Clark Family Data Oct. 8, 1909 And Data on "Cedron" Germantown, PA (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Data on E.W. Clark, Jay Cooke, Edward Dodge, George W. Farnum, Aertsen - and Taylor - Taylor Book (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Frank Wallace and Frederick Clark Letters, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Frederick W. Clark Letters 1989 - Also Frank Wallace Letters (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Ellis Ballard (Lawyer for J.S. Clark) Hathaway et al., 1917-1989 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Byard Clark (Related to F.W. Taylor) 1990 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    Original document and copies
  - Death Dates of Various Clarks for Will Search, 1937-1946 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Data on Joseph L. Ferrell 1866-1881. Ferrell and Jones 1875, Ferrell and Muckle 1881, From Gopsill's Phila. City Directory - Taylor (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Data on Russell Davenport (From Yale University) 1987 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - George V. Cresson Co. - Power Transmitting Machinery Co. Phila, 1894 (Box 9, Folder 80)
    Copy and original document
  - Barton Jenks - (Son of Alfred B. Jenks Who Died in 1850) - Died Dec. 13, 1896 in Mt. Washington Near Baltimore, MD - Justice Family, 1896- 1990 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Paul Lederer and Joseph R. Massden "A Type of Civil War Bayonets" (On Philip Justice of Phila) (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Taylor, Justice, Mitchell Genealogy, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - George Justice in Yardley, PA - Connected to Wright and Taylor Family, 1876-1990 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Data on Justice Family and Taylor Family 1989 (Peter Justice Collins) (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Philip Justice Letters from Peter Justice Collins - 1991, 1880-1991 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - F.W. Taylor Letters to Philip M. Justice 1890-1897 - For Taylor Book, Taylor-Justice (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Justice Family in Colonial Families of Phila - Use For Taylor Book, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Data on Philip S. Justice in Philadelphia, 1891-1897 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Data on Justice, Mitchell Jenks - Phila 1860-1866 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Hexamer Fire Insurance Map of Bridesburg Manufacturing Company 1866 (Connected to Philip Justice Gun Mgt. Civil War) (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Bridesburg Manufacturing Company, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Data on Alfred Jenks and Globe Mill, Phila, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Bridesburg Mgt. Co. (Alfred Jenks and Joseph G. Mitchell), 1858-1869 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Death of Barton H. Jenks (12/15/1896) Related to Bridesburg Mgt. Co. (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Justice and Bayonets, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Philip Middleton Justice Letters to Copy, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Philip S. Justice and William Sellers Land on 1895 Map of Nicetown, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Deed Cyrus Caldwellder to George M. Justice 3/7/1845 - Related to Taylor Family (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Paul S. Lederer and Joseph R. Maroden "A Tale of Civil War Bayonets" For Philip Justice Data (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Church of Latter Day Saints - Data on Justice Family, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - C.N. Taylor, Elizabeth Taylor, and Newbold Land in Middletown Township, Bucks County 1876-1891 -Taylor Land (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Data on Justice and Jenks 1988 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - George Justice Family Tree 1990 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Emelen Hare Miller (Made Time Study for Taylor in 1884) Died Jan. 3, 1941 - Midvale Data (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Sidney Newbold - Born: 3/29/1864, Died: 1/1/1912 - Co Patent Holder with F.W. Taylor - See Letter of Mrs. Hartye to Maxwell Newbold 3/21/91, 1905-1991 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Emelen Hare Miller Letter 12-21-1912 On Miller As Time Study Man in 1885 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Taylor and Emelen Hare Miller 1912 Letters - Taylor Book, Taylor and Miller (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - F.W. Taylor to Emelen Hare Miller 12/23/1912 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Emelen H. Miller to Taylor 12/21/1913 (Time Study at Bethlehem in 1885), 1912 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Elihu Spencer Miller (Related to Emelen H. Miller, Died March 6, 1879) (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Emelen Hare Miller (Born 1859) - Taylor Book, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - 1880 Clark and Grandson (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Data on Atherton B. Wadleigh 1963, Atherton B. Wadleigh and Taylor 1963 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Data on Rawle Family and A.B. Wadleigh 1967 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Atherton Wadleigh Taylor 2/18/03 on Shoveling Studies at Bethlehem Steel, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Data on the Rawle Family (Associated with Taylor), 1898 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Data on Rawle Family and Taylor, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Taylor-Wright Search 1987, Francine Laggini and The Search for F.W. Taylor - Summer 1987 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - James Anderson Wright, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Peter Wright, A Family Record (Related to Taylor) Taylor Book (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Lewis Wright (Originally at Link Belt) 228 Hamilton St., Camden, NJ 1870 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Link Belt Engineering Co. Data - 3/3/88 (Phila), 1988 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Phillips Exeter Academy Letter (9/22/87) on F.W. Taylor and J.A. Wright, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - Notes on Link Belt Engineering 10/11/79, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - Samuel Vauclain and Taylor, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - Joseph Wharton - and Wharton Family Data in Relation to F.W. Taylor, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 127)
- Sanford Thompson Records supplement those already at CU, and William C. Whitney data from the Library of Congress which holds a large amount of information on him. Whitney influenced Taylor through the Manufacturing Investment Co. Whitneys descendan (Box 10)
  - Analysis of Cornell Microfilm on Taylor et al, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Taylor Time Study Forms Compared With Sanford Thompson Forms, 1896-1911 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Philadelphia Data on Companies, Midvale and Taylor - Maps Midvale 1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Thompson-Taylor Paper 1978-1981 (Time Study's Roots) Handwritten Copies, Academy Taylor (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Sanford Thompson and Lester Kaighn Study 1965, Thompson Paper Search - Taylor Book, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Sanford Thompson to Ralph Sawyer on Plans for Houses Dec 10, 1901, Thompson-Sawyer, 1901-1902 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Thompson on Plans for Houses (Wiley and Sons) Feb 1902 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - S. Thompson Marketing Engineering, 1946-1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Sanford Thompson Data, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Photos of Thompson Stop Watch and Watch Book Drawings Fe 21, 1896, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Copies of Original Thompson Papers for "Earth Work" Book with F.W. Taylor, 1903-1914 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Thompson Letters on Frank Gilbreth 1909 (also Taylor Letters) Copies, 1897-1977 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Mrs. Taylor's Letters to Sanford Thompson and Thompson to Mrs. Taylor 1930's and 1940's - Copies, Originals sent to Mrs. Hartye and Stevens Institute of Technology 11/4/94 - For Taylor Book, 1934-1940 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Taylor-Thompson Letters 1897, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Thompson-Taylor Letters 1896 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Thompson and MIT "Concrete Tests" 1903, 1867-1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Concrete Thesis at MIT and Obituary of G.E. Swain - Related to Taylor-Thompson, 1903-1931 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Thompson to Taylor on Shoveling 5/21/02, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Taylor to Thompson - 1908 (on Brick Laying), 1908-1977 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Thompson-Taylor Letters 1898 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Notes for Paper on Thompson-Taylor "Secret Alliance", 1902-1955 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Thompson-Taylor Plans to Use Scientific Management to Build Houses - 1901-1902, 1896-1924 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - List of Thompson Manuscripts April 30, 1901 - Taylor (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Gilbreth-Taylor Correspondence 1901 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Misc. Scientific Mgt. Data, Taylor-Thompson Letters, 1896-1926 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Thompson on Capacity of Dump Carts 4/20/1899, Engineering News p. 249 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Rankine's Tables on Fatigue 1867 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - F.W. Taylor to Thompson on Gilbreth - 1/6/1908 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Taylor-Thompson Correspondence 1901 on Houses (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Sanford Thompson Post War Marketing, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Gopsill's and Correspondence, 1870-1988 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    Copies of original documents and originals
  - Plastering and Sawing Time Studies by Thompson - March 1896 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - 1825 Articles on Power of Human Labor - use for Thompson-Taylor (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Taylor-Thompson Data, 1892-1906 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Letters on Sanford Thompson in Boston 1960 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Sanford Thompson Letters 1901-1902 - Taylor, 1901-1977 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Data for Taylor (by Thompson) on Shoveling, etc., 1896-1990 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Contents of Scrapbook 6 - at Taylor Collection, CDW 4/13/66, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Taylor Data to File 11/5/91, 1901-1991 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Taylor Letters to Thompson, 1900-1929 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Books Mentioned by Sanford Thompson to F.W. Taylor - 1896, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - John Stelling - Thompson and Lichtner Co. 1978 (Box 10, Folder 42)